Guide to the Abe Burrows collection of sound recordings [sound recording]
The New York Public Library. Rodgers and Hammerstein Archives of Recorded Sound.
- Television program appearances., 915984
  - Open end (Television program),., 1959; *LDC 27371; *LDC 27372; *LDC 27373; 915987; Audio from television program from 1959. Guests: Abe Burrows; Henry Morgan; Anna Russell; H. Alan Smith; Walter Slezak; John Sack; John Lodner. Hosted by David Susskind. (After 1967, the title "Open End" was changed to "The David Susskind Show.") Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LTC 9180, *LT-10 9783, *LT-10 9784, *LT-10 9785, *LT-10 12317. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1477.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Morgan, Henry, 1915-; Susskind, David, 1920-; Russell, Anna; Smith, H. Alan; Lodner, John; Sack, John; Slezak, Walter, 1902-; David Susskind Show (Television program)
  - PM East (Television program),., October 25, 1961; *LTC 9200; 915988; Mike Wallace interviews Abe Burrows, Cy Feur, Ernie Martin, Shepherd Mead, Iva Withers, Stubby Kaye, Maurice Zolotow and Martin Gabel about "How to succeed in business without really trying." Includes performances of Burrows' songs and songs from Guys and Dolls. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5698, *LJ-12 5699.; 2 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Wallace, Mike, 1918-; Feur, Cy; Martin, Ernie; Mead, Shepherd; Withers, Iva; Kaye, Stubby; Gable, Martin; Zolotow, Maurice
- Other Burrows material., 915989
  Includes home recordings, recordings of Burrows' songs, and other recordings where Burrows performs or is speaker.
  - Abe Burrows oral history,., 1959; *LTC 9191; *LTC 9192; *LTC 9193; *LTC 9194; *LTC 9195; 915990; "Abe Burrows interview." Columbia University oral history. Abe Burrows discusses his life and career in New York and Hollywood. Unidentified interviewer's voice is low on recording. Last few minutes of each cassette side is cut off.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Columbia University oral history collection. Part IV. Radio pinoeers
  - Abe Burrows oral history. Excerpt., *LTC 9196; 915991; Includes a brief excerpt of Burrows talking with Bing Crosby on Crosby's radio show at the beginning of the tape.; Contents: Bing Crosby Show (Radio program) -- Abe Burrows oral history. Excerpt.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Crosby, Bing, 1904-1977; Bing Crosby show (Radio program); Abe Burrows oral history. Excerpt
  - Abe Burrows songs., *LDC 42526, tracks 1-2; 915992; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5565; Contents: Stationary type song / Abe Burrows -- I'm not sick of you / Abe Burrows.; 1 sound disc: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Stationary type song; I'm not sick of you
  - Abe Burrows songs., *LDC 42526, tracks 4-5; 915993; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5566; Contents: Tokyo Rose / Abe Burrows -- Ron, ron, ron / Abe Burrows.; 1 sound disc: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Tokyo Rose; Ron, ron, ron
  - Abe Burrows songs., 915994; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5567; 1 sound disc: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
  - Abe Burrows songs., *LDC 42526, tracks 10-12; 915995; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5565, *LJ-12 5567; Contents: Waukeshaw natural bridge / Abe Burrows -- Pansy in my garden / Abe Burrows.; 2 sound discs: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Waukeshaw Natural Bridge; Pansy In My Garden
  - Heinz the huntsman / Abe Burrows,., May 3, 1948; *LDC 42526, tracks 17-18; 915996; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5552; 1 sound disc: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
  - Home recording., *LDC 27375; 915997; "Jimmy piano"--Container. "JB plays 'Moonlight Sonata' and misc. AB sings 'Ain't necessarily so' and others. Phil Silvers (sings?) aria"--Inventory list. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12318. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1478.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
  - Home recording., *LDC 27376; 915998; "Jonnie Burrows"--Container. "AB with nephew Jonathon Burrows"--Inventory list. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12320. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1476.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
  - Home recording,., 195-; *LDC 27375; *LDC 27377; 915999; "XMAS 1950, XMAS 1951 up to 148, children Sept. 1953"--Container. "L&J;, AB, CB children sing. Stanley Praeger end of tape w/ AB & CB"--Inventory list. Track listing for CD service copy on file. [2 copies] Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12318, *LT-10 12319. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-5-A 247, *LT-7-A 1480.; 2 sound tape reels: analog, mono.
  - Home recording,., 1953; *LDC 27377; 916000; "Current work" Burrows, solo piano. Includes radio broadcasts of excerpts of classical music. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12319. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-5-A 244.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, paper-based, mono.; 5 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-
  - Home recording,., 1962; *LDC 27376; 916001; "Dad." "AB, CB, CB's father, circa 1962. Discussion of insurance, father's illness, John Glenn and the Civil War"--Inventory list. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12320. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-3-A 25.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 3 in.
    Burrows, Carin
  - Home recording,., December 19, 1950; *LDC 27375; *LDC 27377; 916002; "Santa Claus in front of Macy's"--Container. Track listing for CD service copy on file. [2 copies] Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12318, *LT-10 12319. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-5-A 248, *LT-7-A 1479.; 2 sound tape reels: analog, acetate-based, mono.
  - Home recording,., December 18, 1951; *LDC 27377; 916003; "Children - family Xmas 1950." [On inventory list: "JB says it's 12/18/51"] "L&J;, AB, CB children sing." Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12319. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-5-A 245.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, paper-based, mono.; 5 in.
  - Home recording,., January 6, 1954; *LDC 28828; 916004; "Jimmy's 13th birthday"--Container. "AB intro, piano (Cecile), various family wish him happy birthday."--Inventory list. Track listing on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12368. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1473.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based; 7 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Burrows, James, 1940-
  - Lopin' along / Abe Burrows., *LDC 42526, tracks 19-20; 916005; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5692; 1 sound disc: analog, aluminum-based acetate; 12 in.
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance training record,., September 1962; *LTC 9200; *LZR 7727; 916006; "How to succeed in the life insurance business by trying." Abe Burrows performs to train Met Life employees. On side B of cassette, after the conclusion of PM East.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Metropolitan Life Insurance Company
  - Miscellaneous., *LT-7 6701; 916007; "Current work"--Container. "AB, CB, Claire Trevor, Maurice Zolotow, songs, spoof on Kinsey report"--Inventory list.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips; 7 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Trevor, Claire, 1909-; Zolotow, Maurice
  - Russel Crouse memorial,., May 26, 1966; *LDC 28827; 916008; Recorded at the Broadhurst Theatre, New York City. Speakers: Abe Burrows, chairman; Dorothy Stickney Lindsay; Garson Kanin; Marc Connelly; John Mason Brown; Ethel Merman; Teresa Wright; Sidney Kingsley. Track listing on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 9771, *LT-10 12369. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1474.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based; 7 in.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Lindsay, Dorothy Stickney; Kanin, Garson, 1912-; Connelly, Marc, 1890-; Brown, John Mason, 1900-1969; Merman, Ethel; Wright, Teresa, 1918-; Kingsley, Sidney, 1906-; Crouse, Russel
  - Salute to ASCAP,., May 1, 1966; *LZR 7722; *LZR 7723; *LZR 7724; *LZR 7725; *LZR 7726; 916009; Sponsored by Cue magazine. Held at Philharmonic Hall (Avery Fisher Hall), NYC. Speakers: Abe Burrows, Cy Coleman, Jack Cassidy, Ray Henderson, Leslie Uggams, James van Heusen, Sammy Cahn, Joan Diener, Arthur Schwartz, Hoagy Carmichael, Dinah Shore, Roger Stevens, Emory Lewis, Stanley Adams, Tony Bennett, Burton Lane, Jule Styne, Johnny Desmond, Harry Warren, Jimmy McHugh, Sheila MacRae and Harold Arlen. Includes segment called "The Abe Burrows Story." Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-10 9786, *LT-10 9787, *LT-10 9788.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Coleman, Cy; Cassidy, Jack; Henderson, Ray; Uggams, Leslie; Van Heusen, Jimmy; Cahn, Sammy; Diener, Joan; Schwartz, Arthur, 1900-1984; Carmichael, Hoagy, 1899-; Shore, Dinah, 1917-1994; Stevens, Roger; Lewis, Emory; Adams, Stanley; Bennett, Tony, 1926-; Lane, Burton; Styne, Jule; Desmond, Johnny; Warren, Harry, 1893-; McHugh, Jimmy, 1894-1969; MacRae, Sheila; Arlen, Harold, 1905-1986; Cue Magazine
- Musicals., 916010
  Recordings of excerpts from musicals in which Burrows wrote the book or was somehow involved.
  - Can-can. Selections / Cole Porter., *LDC 42526, tracks 21-22; 916011; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5689; Contents: C'est magnifique -- Allez vous e'n.; 1 sound disc: analog, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    C'est magnifique; Allez vous e'n
  - Can-can. Selections / Cole Porter., *LDC 42530, tracks 1-15; 916012; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5708, *LJ-12 5709 Preservation copy in: *LT-10-A 3312; Contents: Can-can. I love Paris / Cole Porter -- Mont mart -- Can-can. Law / Cole Porter -- Who said gay paree -- Never give anything away -- C'est magnifique -- What a fair thing is a woman -- I am in love -- Her heart is in her work -- We are maidens -- Can can -- Live and let live.; 2 sound discs: analog, aluminum-based acetate; 12 in.
    Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Can-can. I love Paris; Can-can. Law; Mont mart; Who said gay paree; Never give anything away; C'est magnifique; What a fair thing is a woman; I Am In Love; Her heart is in her work; We are maidens; Can can; Live and Let Live
  - How to succeed in business without really trying / Frank Loesser,., February 1971; *LTC 9205; *LTC 9206; 916013; Live performance in Ft. Lauderdale. Book by Abe Burrows. Poor audio quality.; 2 sound cassettes: analog.
  - Jacobowsky., *LTC 9202; *LTC 9203; 916014; Unpublished musical by Abe Burrows. "Frank Music Corp., 119 W. 57 St."; Contents: Here is to you -- I'll be smiling at you -- Motherland -- Is this a man? -- Look at my love -- How clever you are -- Less & less -- Two possibilities -- If I were a woman -- You would make some girl -- We - they -- You I love -- This is how it is -- Watchdog -- Piano player's song -- Love is -- A person is a person -- You sir -- Did you really think.; 2 sound cassettes: analog.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Here is to you; I'll be smiling at you; Motherland; Is this a man?; Look at my love; How clever you are; Less & less; Two possibilities; If I were a woman; You would make some girl; We - they; You I love; This is how it is; Watchdog; Piano player's song; Love Is; A person is a person; You sir; Did you really think
  - Jacobowsky. Selections., *LTC 9204; 916015; Two selections from an unpublished musical by Abe Burrows. Take 4 of "Here's to you"; take 3 of "Lisa."; Contents: Here is to you -- Lisa.; 1 sound cassette: analog.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Here is to you; Lisa
  - Poilu., *LTC 9208; 916016; Song from an unproduced musical?, performed with piano. Demo tape.
  - Tango Mogador. Excerpts., *LTC 9201; 916017; Excerpts of an unproduced musical by Abe Burrows.; Contents: Tango mogador -- Perfect -- La legion -- Seven o'clock -- Whore's Mass -- Think of your father -- Ulrich's love song -- Me of all people -- Military man -- Thinking of her.; 1 sound cassette: analog.
    Burrows, Abe, 1910-; Tango Mogador; Perfect; La legion; Seven o'clock; Whore's Mass; Think of your father; Ulrich's love song; Me of all people; Military Man; Thinking of her
  - Three wishes for Jamie. Selections / Ralph Blane., *LDC 42527; 916018; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5686, *LJ-12 5687, *LJ-12 5688 Preservation copy in: *LT-10-A 3309; Contents: We're for love -- I'll sing you a song -- Tale of the three witches -- Girl that I court in my mind -- Hayride -- My heart's darlin' -- Maybe is a woman's word -- Tis a wonderful thing in nature -- Woman's work -- Sure and it's great to be home -- Trottin' to the fair -- April face.; 3 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    We're for love; I'll sing you a song; Tale of the three witches; Girl that I court in my mind; Hayride; My heart's darlin'; Maybe is a woman's word; Tis a wonderful thing in nature; Woman's work; Sure and it's great to be home; Trottin' to the fair; April face
- Miscellaneous., 916019
  - ASCAP seminar on the musical theater,., October 21, 1962; *LDC 42529; 916020; "WNYC" Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5702, *LJ-12 5703 Preservation copy in: *LT-10-A 3313; 2 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, aluminum-based acetate; 12 in.
  - Cole Porter recordings., *LT-10 9772; 916021; Private recordings of Cole Porter performing his songs.; Contents: Never give anything away -- C'est magnifique -- What a fair thing is a woman -- I love Paris -- Mont mart -- The law -- Who said gay paree -- I am in love -- Her heart is in her work -- We are maidens -- Can can -- I do -- Live and let live.
    Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Never give anything away; C'est magnifique; What a fair thing is a woman; I love Paris; Mont mart; The law; Who said gay paree; I Am In Love; Her heart is in her work; We are maidens; Can can; I Do; Live and Let Live
  - French story. Normans., *LDC 27374; 916022; Excerpt, from the French Broadcasting System. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12317. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1477.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
  - Miscellaneous songs., *LDC 42530, tracks 16-17; 916023; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-10 1777 Preservation copy in: *LT-10-A 3312; Contents: Just a moment ago -- Old enough to know bettor [sic].; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, aluminum-based acetate; 10 in.
    Just a moment ago; Old enough to know bettor
  - Miscellaneous., *LDC 27376; 916024; "AB on Jack Parr, 6/22/61" written inside container, but tape appears to be an unsolicited recording sent to Abe Burrows by George Burke from Cranston, RI. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12320. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-5-A 243.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 5 in.
    Burke, George
  - Miscellaneous., *LDC 27376; 916025; "Mostly muzak. Approx. 1 minute of AB playing 'April in Paris'"--Inventory list. Tune? -- Burrows -- Sleeping Beauty / Tchaikovsky -- Moulin Rouge / Percy Faith -- Nocturne / Katchaturian; Boston Pops -- Fancy Free -- John McCormack; Laura O'Neill. Only the "April in Paris" segment has been transferred to the preservation and service copies Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12320. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1481.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
  - Miscellaneous., *LDC 28828; 916026; "Old master tape"--Container. "Peter Lind Hayes (signed?), various routines w/ Mary Hayes and others"--Inventory list. Track listing on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12368. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1475.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, acetate-based; 7 in.
    Hayes, Peter Lynde
  - Secret file USA., *LDC 27374; 916027; Excerpt, with Robert Alda. Track listing for CD service copy on file. Preservation copy in: *LT-10 12317. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LT-7-A 1477.; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips, acetate-based, mono.; 7 in.
    Alda, Robert
  - Songs for children / Kay Swift., *LDC 42526, tracks 23-31; 916028; Sung by Louise Carlyle. Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5690, *LJ-12 5691; Contents: Reaching for the brass ring -- Sleepy song -- Bath time -- Smiling Betsy -- John likes it when the wind blows -- My teeny restaurant -- Ridin' his bike -- Upside down -- I've got a horse.; 2 sound discs: analog, 78 rpm, aluminum-based acetate, mono.; 12 in.
    Carlyle, Louise; Reaching for the Brass Ring; Sleepy song; Bath time; Smiling Betsy; John Likes it When the Wind Blows; My Teeny Restaurant; Ridin' his bike; Upside down; I've Got a Horse
  - Songs. Selections / Robert Emmett Dolan., *LDC 42528; 916029; Access to original items restricted. Original in: *LJ-12 5710, *LJ-12 5711 Preservation copy in: *LT-10-A 3310; 2 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, aluminum-based acetate; 12 in.